The next two topics will focus on indexing.
Indexing helps speed up queries within a table
so long as the indexes are done with some
strategic purpose. To best define an index,
think of your local library for just a moment.
Books are stored by some type of classification,
usually the Dewey Decimal Classification. This
classification system helps to organize books
and make them easier to find. Such an index can
also be added to a table. This type of index is
a clustered index and is automatically added to
a table's primary key if one exists. I have a
BikeRepairs table that I created elsewhere in this
course, and the table currently has no indexes.
I will find and expand this table, select and
hold (or right-click) Indexes, select New Index,
Clustered Index, and in this New
Index window, I will do two things.
First, I will select the Unique check
box under Clustered. Then, I will select
Add, select the check box next
to the BikeRepairID column,
select the OK button, and before we select the
OK button here, I want to show you how you can
generate a script working with one of these
windows. I will select the Script drop-down arrow,
and we can generate the SQL code used
to create this index to a new window,
file, or just the clipboard. I will
select New Query Editor Window,
select the OK button, and not only has this
index been created, but look at the code used to
generate a clustered index in ascending order on
the BikeRepairID field. This table will now store
information in the order of the BikeRepairID,
making queries that utilize this field run faster.